<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bulletins group="centralbanking">
  <title>OH! G.O.D.</title>
  <subtitle>Governors Of Demand</subtitle>
  <authors>
    <author>Giulia Fracas</author>
    <author>Francesca Polini</author>
  </authors>
  <bulletin id="07" date="20160423">
    <sections>
      <section>
        <title>ECB organization</title>
        <chapter>
          <title>Schedules for the meetings of the Governing Council and General Council of the ECB 2016</title>
        </chapter>
        <table>
          <row type="head">
            <cell>Month</cell>
            <cell>Day</cell>
          </row>
          <row type="cell">
            <cell>January</cell>
            <cell>21</cell>
        </row>
        <row type="cell">
          <cell>February</cell>
          <cell></cell>
      </row>
      <row type="cell">
        <cell>March</cell>
        <cell>10</cell>
    </row>
    <row type="cell">
      <cell>April</cell>
      <cell>21</cell>
  </row>
  <row type="cell">
    <cell>May</cell>
    <cell>18</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>June</cell>
  <cell>02, 22, 23</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>July</cell>
  <cell>06, 21</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>August</cell>
  <cell>03</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>September</cell>
  <cell>08, 21, 22</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>October</cell>
  <cell>05</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>November</cell>
  <cell>02, 16</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
  <cell>December</cell>
  <cell>08, 14, 15</cell>
</row>
        </table>
        <chapter>
          <title>The General Council</title>
          <paragraph>The General Council comprises:</paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <list type="unordered">
              <item>The President of the ECB</item>
              <item>The Vice-President of the ECB</item>
              <item>The governors of the national central banks (NCBs) of the 28 EU Member States</item>
            </list>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>In other words, it includes representatives of the 19 Euro Area countries and the 9 non-euro area countries. The other members of the ECB's Executive Board, the President of the EU Council and one member of the European Commission may attend the meetings of the General Council but do not have the right to vote. In accordance with the Statute of the European System of Central Banks and of the European Central Bank, the General Council will be dissolved once all EU Member States have introduced the single currency.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Governing Council</title>
          <paragraph>The Governing Council is the main decision-making body of the ECB. It consists of:</paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <list type="unordered">
            <item>The six members of the Executive Board</item>
            <item>The governors of the national central banks of the 19 Euro Area countries</item>
          </list>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>The Governing Council usually meets twice a month at the ECB’s premises in Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
          <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
          <keyword name="Governance" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>On 21st April Mario Draghi's speech</title>
        <chapter>
          <title>13.45 What about monetary policy?</title>
          <paragraph>Ladies and gentlemen, the Vice-President and I are very pleased to welcome you to our press conference. We will now report on the outcome of today’s meeting of the Governing Council.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>14.35</title>
          <paragraph>Based on our regular economic and monetary analyses, we decided to keep the key ECB interest rates unchanged. We continue to expect them to remain at present or lower levels for an extended period of time, and well past the horizon of our net asset purchases.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <table>
          <row type="head">
            <cell>Date</cell>
            <cell>Deposit facility</cell>
            <cell>Main refinancing operations</cell>
        </row>
        <row type="cell">
        <cell>March 16th 2016</cell>
        <cell>-0.40</cell>
        <cell>0.00</cell>
      </row>
      <row type="cell">
      <cell>December 9th 2015</cell>
      <cell>-0.30</cell>
      <cell>0.05</cell>
    </row>
    <row type="cell">
    <cell>September 10th 2014</cell>
    <cell>-0.20</cell>
    <cell>0.05</cell>
  </row>
  <row type="cell">
  <cell>June 11th 2014</cell>
  <cell>-0.10</cell>
  <cell>0.15</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
<cell>November 13rd 2013</cell>
<cell>0.00</cell>
<cell>0.25</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
<cell>May 8th 2013</cell>
<cell>0.00</cell>
<cell>0.50</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
<cell>July 11th 2012</cell>
<cell>0.00</cell>
<cell>0.75</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
<cell>December 14th 2011</cell>
<cell>0.25</cell>
<cell>1.00</cell>
</row>
<row type="cell">
<cell>November 9th 2011</cell>
<cell>0.50</cell>
<cell>0.25</cell>
</row>
        </table>
        <chapter>
          <title>Non standard monetary policy</title>
          <paragraph>Regarding non-standard monetary policy measures we have started to expand our monthly purchases under the asset purchase programme to €80 billion, from the previous amount of €60 billion. As stated before, these purchases are intended to run until the end of March 2017, or beyond, if necessary, and in any case until the Governing Council sees a sustained adjustment in the path of inflation consistent with its inflation aim.</paragraph>
          <paragraph>The expanded asset purchase programme (APP) adds the purchase programme for public sector securities to the existing private sector asset purchase programmes to address the risks of a too prolonged period of low inflation. It consists of:</paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <list type="unordered">
            <item>Third covered bond purchase programme (CBPP3)</item>
          <item>Asset-backed securities purchase programme (ABSPP)</item>
          <item>Public sector purchase programme (PSPP)</item>
          </list>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>The primary objective of the ECB’s monetary policy is to maintain price stability. The ECB aims at inflation rates of below, but close to, 2% over the medium term.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <graph unit="%" x="date" y="number">
          <title>Inflation Euro Area</title>
          <dataset label= "inflation">
            <data x="200001" y="1.9"/>
            <data x="200004" y="1.7"/>
            <data x="200007" y="2.1"/>
            <data x="200010" y="2.4"/>
          </dataset>
          <dataset label= "inflation">
            <data x="200501" y="1.9"/>
            <data x="200504" y="2.1"/>
            <data x="200507" y="2.1"/>
            <data x="200510" y="2.4"/>
          </dataset>
          <dataset label= "inflation">
            <data x="201001" y="0.9"/>
            <data x="201004" y="1.6"/>
            <data x="201007" y="1.7"/>
            <data x="201010" y="2.2"/>
          </dataset>
          <dataset label= "inflation">
            <data x="201501" y="-0.6"/>
            <data x="201504" y="0.0"/>
            <data x="201507" y="0.2"/>
            <data x="201510" y="0.2"/>
          </dataset>
      </graph>
      <chapter>
        <paragraph>Average 1.77%</paragraph>
        <paragraph>Start of stage three of EMU (the line on the chart) Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) represents a major step in the integration of EU economies. It involves the coordination of economic and fiscal policies, a common monetary policy, and a common currency, the euro.</paragraph>
      </chapter>
      <graph unit="%" x="country" y="number">
        <dataset label= "Inflation rate by countries">
          <data x="AT" y="0.6"/>
          <data x="BE" y="1.5"/>
          <data x="CY" y="-2.1"/>
          <data x="DE" y="-0.3"/>
          <data x="EE" y="0.0"/>
          <data x="ES" y="-1.2"/>
          <data x="FI" y="0.3"/>
          <data x="FR" y="-0.1"/>
          <data x="GR" y="-0.4"/>
          <data x="IE" y="-0.2"/>
          <data x="IT" y="-0.4"/>
          <data x="LU" y="-0.6"/>
          <data x="MT" y="0.8"/>
          <data x="NL" y="-0.2"/>
          <data x="PT" y="0.5"/>
          <data x="SI" y="-0.7"/>
          <data x="SK" y="-0.4"/>
      </dataset>
    </graph>
    <chapter>
      <title>Open market operations</title>
      <paragraph>The targeted longer-term refinancing operations (TLTROs) are Eurosystem operations that provide financing to credit institutions for periods of up to four years. They offer long-term funding at attractive conditions to banks in order to further ease private sector credit conditions and stimulate bank lending to the real economy. The TLTROs, therefore, reinforce the ECB’s current accommodative monetary policy stance and strengthen the transmission of monetary policy by further incentivising bank lending to the real economy.</paragraph>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <title>A programmed operations</title>
      <paragraph>A first series of TLTROs was announced on 5 June 2014 and a second series (TLTRO-II) on 10 March 2016. The second series of the TLTRO programme consists of four targeted longer-term refinancing operations (TLTRO-II), each with a maturity of four years, starting in June 2016. Borrowing conditions in these operations can be as low as the interest rate on the deposit facility.</paragraph>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
      <paragraph>Euro Area -0.2%</paragraph>
      <paragraph>The risks to the euro area growth outlook still remain tilted to the downside. Our recent monetary policy decisions have improved overall financing conditions, which should support the outlook for consumption and investment. However, uncertainties persist and relate, in particular, to developments in the global economy and to geopolitical risks. The reafter, supported by our monetary policy measures and the expected economic recovery, inflation rates should recover further in 2017 and 2018.</paragraph>
    </chapter>
    <keywords>
      <keyword name="Western Europe" />
      <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
      <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
      <keyword name="Governance" />
      <keyword name="Inflation/Deflation" />
      <keyword name="Unconventional Monetary Policies" />
    </keywords>
    <sources>
      <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
    </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>14.38 Economic analysis</title>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>Let me now explain our assessment in greater detail, starting with the economic analysis. Euro area real GDP increased by 0.3%, quarter on quarter, in the fourth quarter of 2015, supported by domestic demand, while being dampened by relatively weak export trends. Incoming data for the first quarter of 2016 point to ongoing output growth, at a pace broadly similar to that in the final quarter of 2015. Moreover, our accommodative monetary policy stance, continued employment gains resulting from past structural reforms and the still relatively low price of oil should provide ongoing support for households’ real disposable income and private consumption.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <graph unit="%" x="string" y="number">
          <dataset label= "EU consumer confidence">
          <data x="Actual" y="-9.3"/>
          <data x="Apr-Jun" y="-7.65"/>
          <data x="Jul-Sep" y="-5.32"/>
          <data x="Oct-Dec" y="-5.32"/>
          <data x="2020" y="1.4"/>
        </dataset>
        </graph>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
          <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
          <keyword name="Commerce" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>14.40 Inflation purposes</title>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>According to Eurostat, euro area annual HICP inflation in March 2016 was 0.0%, compared with -0.2% in February, reflecting mainly a rise in services price inflation. Looking ahead, on the basis of current futures prices for energy, inflation rates could turn negative again in the coming months before picking up in the second half of 2016. Thereafter, supported by our monetary policy measures and the expected economic recovery, inflation rates should recover further in 2017 and 2018.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
          <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
          <keyword name="Inflation/Deflation" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
          <source>tradingeconomics.com</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>14.43 Do all works well?</title>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>Overall, the monetary policy measures in place since June 2014 have clearly improved borrowing conditions for firms and households, as well as credit flows across the euro area. The comprehensive package of new monetary policy measures adopted in March this year underpins the ongoing upturn in loan growth, thereby supporting the recovery of the real economy.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <graph unit="%" x="string" y="number">
          <title>EU household credit growth</title>
          <dataset label= "loans growth">
            <data x="Actual" y="1.6"/>
            <data x="Apr-Jun" y="1.9"/>
            <data x="Jul-Sep" y="2"/>
            <data x="Oct-Dec" y="2.75"/>
            <data x="2020" y="3.2"/>
        </dataset>
        </graph>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
          <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
          <keyword name="Loans" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
          <source>tradingeconomics.com</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>14.46 Fiscal policies</title>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>They Should also support the economic recovery, while remaining in compliance with the fiscal rules of the European Union. Full and consistent implementation of the Stability and Growth Pact is crucial to maintain confidence in the fiscal framework. At the same time, all countries should strive for a more growth-friendly composition of fiscal policies.</paragraph>
          <paragraph>14.47 We are now at your disposal for questions.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Helicopter money false myth</title>
          <paragraph>We haven't really thought or talked about it. It's a very interesting concept that is now being discussed by academic economists and in various environments. But we haven’t studied the concept. It clearly involves complexities, both accounting-wise, legal-wise; and it may mean different things to different people. The concept is fraught with operational, legal and institutional difficulties. But the bottom line is we have never discussed it.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>The central bank said instead that it would start purchasing corporate bonds as part of its quantitative easing program in June. The purchases will be carried out on the ECB's behalf by the national banks of Belgium, Germany, Spain, France, Italy and Finland, according to a statement issued after Draghi's conference.
The purchases will take place in the primary and secondary markets. To be eligible, instruments must be denominated in euros and have a credit rating of at least BBB- or equivalent; they must also have a remaining maturity of between six months and 30 years at the time of purchase.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Expanded asset purchase programme (APP)</title>
          <paragraph>Purchases of marketable debt instruments increase the Eurosystem holdings and inject liquidity into the banking system in order to meet the Governing Council's monthly purchase target of €80 billion (from March 2015 until March 2016 this figure was €60 billion).</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <table>
          <row type="head">
          <cell>Eurosystem holdings</cell>
          <cell>APP</cell>
        </row>
        <row type="cell">
          <cell>April 2016</cell>
          <cell>917,817</cell>
      </row>
      <row type="cell">
        <cell>Monthly net purchases</cell>
        <cell>85,246</cell>
    </row>
    <row type="cell">
      <cell>Quarter-end amortisation adjustment</cell>
      <cell>0</cell>
  </row>
  <row type="cell">
    <cell>May 2016</cell>
    <cell>1,003,063</cell>
</row>
        </table>
        <chapter>
          <title>Independence declared</title>
          <paragraph>We have a mandate to pursues price stability for the whole of the euro — not only for Germany. This mandate is established by the treaty by European law. We obey the law, not the politicians, because we are independent as stated by the law.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Eastern Europe" />
          <keyword name="Global Corporations" />
          <keyword name="Unconventional Monetary Policies" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>ecb.europa.eu</source>
          <source>tradingeconomics.com</source>
          <source>cnbc.com</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>14.56 Atlante Fund revival</title>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>We haven't yet examined completely the details of this. I can say it's a small step in the right direction. Atlante, a new private initiative backed by the Italian government, is designed to stop the sky falling in. The fund, which takes its name from the mythological titan who held up the heavens, will buy shares in Italian lenders in a bid to edge the sector away from a fully-fledged crisis.</paragraph>
          <paragraph>Many Italian banks and other financial institutions have agreed to contribute money for the creation of a “rescue” fund, which will be named “Atlante”. Atlante is a € 4.25bn fund that will participate to the subscription of the upcoming capital increases of Italian banks seeking recapitalizations and that will take actions to revive the NPL market in Italy. But Italian banks have made €200bn of loans to borrowers now deemed insolvent, of which €85bn has not been written down on their balance sheets. A broader measure of non-performing debt, which includes loans unlikely to be repaid in full, stands at €360bn, according to the Bank of Italy. So is Atlante — with about €5bn of equity — really enough to keep the heavens in place?</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <graph unit="EUR" x="date" y="number">
          <title>European securization issuance</title>
          <dataset label= "€bn">
            <data x="2010" y="397"/>
            <data x="2011" y="396"/>
            <data x="2012" y="258"/>
            <data x="2013" y="180"/>
            <data x="2014" y="220"/>
            <data x="2015" y="210"/>
        </dataset>
        </graph>
        <chapter>
          <paragraph>Market participants say the securitisation scheme stands to play a role in relieving banks of their bad loans, with a government guarantee helping to bridge the gap between private equity offers for NPLs and the asking price of the banks.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Participants</title>
          <paragraph>The new Atlante fund for Italy's bank sector aims to obtain 3 billion euros from Italy's healthy banks, with giants Intesa SanPaolo and Unicredit chipping in about one billion each, various qualified sources said on Wednesday.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Aims</title>
          <paragraph>As noted above, the fund has raised a total of €4.25bn. This amount could potentially but unlikely be more than doubled, as Atlante will be able to lever itself up to 110% (but at what cost?). According to Quaestio SGR, at least 30% of the fund will be used to buy the more junior tranches of securitized NPLs, while up to 70% will be devoted to investments in banks (i.e. to back recapitalizations).
The fund will have a 5-year horizon, with the possibility of extending to 6, 7, or 8 on an annual basis, and is offering a 6% return per annum.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>First operation</title>
          <paragraph>Veneto Banca SpA, which needs to raise 1 billion euros ($1.1 billion) to ensure its survival, said the Italy-orchestrated bailout fund Atlante has guaranteed it will buy any leftover stock as investors spurn the initial public offering.
The bank, based outside Treviso, Italy, said it will offer shares at 10 euro cents to 50 cents apiece in a sale that will begin June 8, according to an e-mailed statement on Tuesday. The range isn’t in line with market practice because of weak demand, the bank said. Atlante pledged to buy all unsold stock as long as it gets a controlling stake of at least 50.1% of Veneto Banca.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Governance" />
          <keyword name="Unconventional Monetary Policies" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>bloomberg.com</source>
          <source>soldionline.it</source>
          <source>ansa.it</source>
          <source>bsic.it</source>
          <source>ft.com</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Brexit</title>
        <chapter>
          <title>Brexit opinions</title>
          <paragraph>Let me state unequivocally that we view the participation of the UK in the European Union as mutually beneficial, and we will continue to say so in the coming weeks. Certainly the discussion about this possibility has already produced some significant consequences on the markets, for example a depreciation of sterling, quite significant. We do expect a continuation of market volatility, certainly until the referendum.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <graph unit="%" x="string" y="percentage">
          <dataset label= "brexit opinions">
          <data x="remain" y="51"/>
          <data x="don't know" y="3"/>
          <data x="leave" y="46"/>
        </dataset>
        </graph>
        <chapter>
          <title>About sterling depreciation</title>
          <paragraph>The GBP’s price action suggests that the market is already worrying about the EU referendum and the associated threat of 'Brexit. Add to this an unexpected under-performance in the UK economy since the start of 2016 and we can see why the pound has fallen to the degree it has.
The pound to euro exchange rate is down about 5% since the ECB’s December meeting while the pound to dollar exchange rate has fallen from 1.56 in late summer to 1.45 now.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <chapter>
          <title>Will the pound fall further?</title>
          <paragraph>Experts think so. Deutsche Bank said late last year that the pound was one of the most overvalued currencies in the world. It believes sterling will drop to $1.28 against the greenback by the end of this year. Citi believes the pound could fall to as low as $1.35 against the dollar, while Saxo Bank believes it will drop to $1.30 by the end of this year. This isn't just because of Brexit risks. Economists believe Britain's large current account deficit, which measures the difference between money flowing in and out of the UK, has left Britain vulnerable to shocks.</paragraph>
          <paragraph>15.27 Conference end.</paragraph>
        </chapter>
        <keywords>
          <keyword name="Western Europe" />
          <keyword name="Governance" />
          <keyword name="Brexit/Grexit" />
          <keyword name="Currencies" />
        </keywords>
        <sources>
          <source>bloomberg.com</source>
          <source>telegraph.co.uk</source>
          <source>ft.com</source>
          <source>soldionline.it</source>
        </sources>
      </section>
    </sections>
  </bulletin>
</bulletins>
